now let's work on some more examples
graphing quadratic functions in standard
form
now we did one example
using the data table
and there are some other things that you
may need to find such as the x-intercept
and the y-intercept
but i think it's still good to like put
that information in the form of a data
table it's simply helpful
the first thing we should do is find a
vertex
which is
negative b over
2a b is negative 4.
a is the number in front of x squared so
a is 1.
so this is going to be 2 times 1. so
that's going to be positive 4 divided by
2.
so the vertex
has an x value of 2.
let's just put that in the data table
now let's find a y value when x is 2.
so two squared minus four times two plus
three
so that's four minus eight plus three
four minus eight is negative four plus
three that's negative one
so that's the y value of the vertex
now let's find the x-intercepts in order
to find the x-intercepts
set y equal to zero and factor
two numbers that multiply to three but
add to negative four
are negative one and negative three
so it's going to be x minus one
and x minus three therefore the
x-intercepts are one
and three
which means x is one y is zero
so we have the points one zero and three
zero
now let's find the y intercept
to do that replace x with zero
so you can see that it's going to be 3.
so we have the point 0
comma 3.
notice that these two are the same
because they're equidistant from the
vertex
so if we have the .03 then when x is 4 y
must be 3 as well
because 0 and 4 are equidistant from the
vertex
so now we have everything that we need
in order to graph this function
so let's plot it
starting with the vertex it's 2 negative
and then the x-intercepts are 3 0
and 1 0 that's where it touches the
x-axis the y-intercept is 0 3 that's
where the curve touches the y-axis and
we have the 0.43
and so
the graph
is going to look something like this
we can see that the axis of symmetry
is x is equal to 2
the x coordinate of the vertex
the minimum value
is negative one
and so the range
will vary from negative one to infinity
and the domain is always going to be the
same
all real numbers
and so that's it for
graphing functions
in standard form